In many apps you develop, you may need to
capture input from the person running the
app. This input can be as simple as asking for
a name to as complex as answering questions in
a trivia game with code and then determining what
to do with that captured input. For our first use
of the input keyword, we will go with the asking
for a name example, as seen here in the 321-input
file. I have a very simple two-line code example,
and on the first line, we see the input function,
which has, in quotes, a prompt, in this case,
asking for a first name. Notice that this input
is stored inside a player name variable.
Typically, one will want to save an input
for later use, hence the reason for capturing
this information into a variable. In gaming,
a game often wants a player's name at the start
of a game. Line 2 shows a print statement showing
a welcome message and the player’s name. I will
run this code. And I am prompted to enter my name,
which I will, and then select the Enter
key on the keyboard. The code works,
but do you notice two slight adjustments
we should make to this presentation? First,
we should put a space between the prompt and the
place where a name is entered. I will add that
space within the quotes on line 1. Next, we need a
comma between the welcome greeting and the name on
line 2. Sometimes, code adjustments are merely
cosmetic adjustments to literal text. I will
make that adjustment, rerun the code, and enter
my name; the output looks good now. Remember,
automatic spacing only happens when concatenating
values using a comma, which explains why we had a
space between the welcome message and
the name, but not after the prompt.